<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Airplanes News and Data</string>
    <string name="menu_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="image">Thumbnail</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_news">News</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display787">Boeing 787</string>
    <string name="b787a">The Boeing 7E7 was announced on 29th January 2003 following the cancellation of the Sonic Cruiser. The aircraft was renamed the Boeing 787 in 2005.\n\n
This important design marked a major shift in technology for Boeing, which aimed for maximum fuel efficiency in a number of ways. Chief among these was a radical change of construction material, with much of the aircraft being built of carbon fibre reinforced plastic (CFRP). Additionally, the fuselage was produced as \'barrels\' rather than sheets of material, reducing the number of fastenings required. This further increased the weight savings. Many of the aircraft\'s systems are now electrically operated, replacing the heavier hydraulic systems of earlier Boeing designs with lighter technology.\n\n
The engines are new designs with increased fuel efficiency. Both the General Electric GEnx and Rolls-Royce Trent 1000 designs are available. Boeing decided to use bleedless designs, another major change for aircraft of this class. Interestingly, Airbus decided not to use bleedless technology on its competing Airbus A350 design and it remains to be seen which approach offers the greatest benefits over the other. The rear engine nacelle has a distinctive rippled look which reduces noise as the engine exhaust and external air mix.\n\n
For passengers, there have been a number of technology improvements. Most noticeably, the windows are amongst the largest in a civil airliner and are lower on the fuselage than is usual, so that passengers have a better view downwards. The lighting system use LED technology allowing each customer great flexibility on the lighting schemes it can use. The pressurisation system features a lower cabin altitude than normal and allows increased humidity, both factors which will contribute to passenger comfort during a long flight.\n\n
With all these technology advances and a distributed manufacturing program that was very new to Boeing, it is not suprising that the program encountered a number of delays. However, the first aircraft was delivered to a customer, All Nippon Airways, in September 2011.\n\n</string>
    <string name="b787b">787-8 - Two General Electric GEnx, or Rolls-Royce Trent 1000s.\n\n</string>
    <string name="b787preformance">Typical cruising speed 913km/h (490kt).\nMaximum speed 954km/h (515kt).\nMaximum range 15,200km (8200nm).</string>
    <string name="b787weights">787-8 - Empty 110,000kg (242,000lb), max takeoff 228,000kg (502,500lb).</string>
    <string name="b787dimensions">787-8 - Wing span 60.00m (197ft 0in), length 56.70m (186ft 0in), height 16.9m (55ft 6in). Wing area 325m2 (3501sq ft).</string>
    <string name="b787capacity">Flightcrew of two. Passenger seating is typically between 210 and 250 depending on customer layout.
Underfloor cargo capacity for up to 28 LD3 containers.</string>
    <string name="b787production">By Summer of 2011 there were over 700 orders for the 787-8 and 787-9 models. Deliveries to customers began in September 2011, with a 787-8 being received by All Nippon Airways.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_boeing">Boeing</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_boeing_news">Boeing News</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_airbus">DisplayAirbus</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_airbus_news">Airbus News</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_bombardier">Bombardier</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_bombardier_news">Bombardier News</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_embraer">Embraer</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_embraer_news">Embraer News</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_atr">ATR</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_md">McDonnell Douglas</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_lockheed">Lockheed</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_tupolev">Tupolev</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_sukhoi">Sukhoi</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_ilyushin">Ilyushin</string>
    <string name="title_activity_a318">A318</string>
    <string name="a318_intro">The Airbus A318 is the smallest member of the Airbus A320 family, a family of short- to medium-range, narrow-body, commercial passenger jet airliners manufactured by Airbus Industrie. The A318 carries up to 132 passengers and has a maximum range of 3,100 nmi (5,700 km; 3,600 mi). Final assembly of the aircraft takes place in Toulouse, France.
The aircraft shares a common type rating with all other Airbus A320 family variants, allowing existing A320 family pilots to fly the aircraft without the need for further training. It is the largest commercial aircraft certified by the European Aviation Safety Agency for steep approach operations, allowing flights at airports such as London City.
The A318 entered service in July 2003 with Frontier Airlines. Relative to other Airbus A320 family variants, it has sold in only small numbers with total orders for only 81 aircraft placed at 30 November 2012.\n\n</string>
    <string name="a318_history">Airbus initial efforts at developing a 100 seat airliner were focused on the all new AE31X program (covering the baseline 95 seat AE316 and 115-125 seat AE317) which Airbus and Alenia, as Airbus Industrie Asia, were developing in conjunction with AVIC of China and Singapore Technologies. The AE31X program arose out of earlier Chinese and South Korean studies for a 100 seater and a framework agreement covering its development was signed in May 1997. However on September 3 1998 Airbus announced termination of the project saying it was not economically viable.
The AE31X would have flown in mid 2002 and entered service in mid 2003. Final assembly would have been undertaken at Xian in China by Xian Aircraft Company./n/n
Even before the cancellation of the AE31X program Airbus had been independently studying a minimum change 100 seat derivative of the A319 covered by the A319M5 designation (M5 = minus five fuselage frames). Following the AE31X\'s cancellation Airbus announced the commercial launch of the A319M5 as the A318 at the 1998 Farnborough Airshow./n/n
Compared with the A319, the A318 is 4.5 frames shorter, reducing standard two class seating from 124 to 107. The A318\'s other significant new feature will be its powerplant, the newly developed Pratt &amp; Whitney PW-6000 (being developed in the 67-102kN/15-23,000lb thrust class), but the CFM International CFM56-5 is also available. Other changes will include a small dorsal fin added to the tail, modified wing camber, and a reduced size cargo door.
Otherwise the A318 will retain much commonality with the rest of the A320 family, including the advanced flightdeck with side stick controllers and fly-by-wire flight controls allowing a common type rating, and the same six abreast fuselage cross section.
The first flight was made on January 15, 2002 from Hamburg-Finkenwerder.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_a319">A319</string>
    <string name="a319_intro">The A319 is one of the smaller members of Airbus\' highly successful single aisle airliner family currently in service, and competes with Boeing\'s 737-300 and 737-700.
The A319 program was launched at the Paris Airshow in June 1993 on the basis of just six orders placed by ILFC late in 1992 and the predicted better prospects of the commercial airliner market, which were certainly realised. The first A319 airline order came from French carrier Air Inter (since merged into Air France), whose order for six was announced in February 1994. Since then Swissair, Air Canada, Lufthansa, Northwest, United, US Airways and British Airways are among the major customers that have ordered more than 500 A319s (all also operate or have on order A320s).
The A319 flew for the first time on August 25 1995 from Hamburg in Germany. European JAA certification and service entry, with Swissair, took place in April 1996.
The A319 is a minimum change, shortened derivative of the highly successful A320. The major difference between the A320 and A319 is that the latter is shorter by seven fuselage frames, while in almost all other respects the A319 and A320 are identical.</string>
    <string name="a319_history">Like the A321, A330 and A340, the A319 features Airbus\' common two crew glass cockpit with sidestick controllers first introduced on the A320. There are significant crew training cost benefits and operational savings from this arrangement as the A319, A320 and A321 can all be flown by pilots with the same type rating, meaning that the same flightcrew pool can fly any of the three types. Further, the identical cockpit means reduced training times for crews converting to the larger A330 and A340. The A319 is said to have the longest range in this category of airliner.
Like the A321, A319 final assembly takes place in Hamburg with DaimlerChrysler Aerospace Airbus. Final assembly of all other Airbus airliners, including the A320, takes place at Toulouse.
The A319 forms the basis for the new baby of the Airbus family, the A318 100 seater, and the Airbus A319 Corporate Jetliner.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_a320">A320</string>
    <string name="a320t1">Perhaps the most important contributor to Airbus Industrie\'s success as an airliner manufacturer, the four member A320 family is a significant sales success and a technological trailblazer. The 150 seat A320 is the foundation and best selling member of the family.
The A320 is perhaps best known as the first airliner to introduce a fly-by-wire flight control system - where control inputs from the pilot are transmitted to the flying surfaces by electronic signals rather than mechanical means. Apart from a small weight saving, the advantage of Airbus\' fly-by-wire is that as it is computer controlled, an inbuilt flight envelope protection makes it virtually impossible to exceed certain flight parameters such as G limits and the aircraft\'s maximum and minimum operating speeds and angle of attack limits.
Also integral to the A320 is the advanced electronic flightdeck, with six fully integrated EFIS colour displays and innovative sidestick controllers rather than conventional control columns. The A320 also employs a relatively high percentage of composite materials compared to earlier designs. Two engines are offered, the CFM56 and IAE V2500.</string>
    <string name="a320t2">The A320 program was launched in March 1982, first flight occurred on February 22 1987, while certification was awarded on February 26 1988. Launch customer Air France took delivery of its first A320 in March that year. The first V2500 engined A320 was delivered to Adria Airways in May 1989.
The initial production version was the A320-100, which was built in only small numbers before being replaced by the definitive A320-200 (certificated in November 1988) with increased max takeoff weight, greater range and winglets. The stretched A321 and shortened A319 and A318 are described separately. All four share a common pilot type rating. Mid 2000 A320 family production was at a monthly rate of 22, to be increased to 30 units a month by the end of 2002.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_a321">A321</string>
    <string name="a321t1">Like the shortened A319, the A321 is a minimum change, in this case stretched, development of the successful A320.
The A321 program was launched in November 1989 and the first development aircraft first flew on March 11 1993. European certification was awarded in December that year.
Compared with the A320 the A321\'s major change is the stretched fuselage, with forward and rear fuselage plugs totalling 6.93m (22ft 9in) (front plug immediately forward of wing 4.27m/14ft, rear plug directly behind the wing 2.67m/8ft 9in).
Other changes include strengthening of the undercarriage to cope with the higher weights, more powerful engines, a simplified and refined fuel system and larger tyres for better braking. A slightly modified wing with double slotted flaps and modifications to the flight controls allows the A321\'s handling characteristics to closely resemble the A320\'s. The A321 features an identical flightdeck to that on the A319 and A320, and shares the same type rating as the smaller two aircraft.</string>
    <string name="a321t2">The basic A321-100 features a reduction in range compared to the A320 as extra fuel tankage was not added to the initial design to compensate for the extra weight. To overcome this Airbus launched the longer range, heavier A321-200 development in 1995 which has a full pax transcontinental US range. This is achieved through higher thrust V2533-A5 or CFM56-5B3 engines and minor structural strengthening and 2900 litres (766US gal/638Imp gal) greater fuel capacity with the installation of an ACT (additional centre tank).
The A321-200 first flew from Daimler Benz (now DaimlerChrysler) Aerospace\'s Hamburg facilities in December 1996.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_a330">A330</string>
    <string name="a330t1">The A330-200 is the newest member of Airbus\' widebody twinjet family and is a long range, shortened development of the standard A330, developed in part as a replacement for the A300-600R and a competitor to the 767-300ER.
Airbus launched development of the A330-200 in November 1995, followed by the first customer order, for 13 from ILFC, placed in February 1996. First flight was on August 13 1997, with certification and first customer deliveries,to ILFC/Canada 3000, in April 1998.
The A330-200 is based on the A330-300 and shares near identical systems, airframe, flightdeck and wings, the only major difference being the fuselage length. Compared with the 300 the A330-200 is 10 frames shorter, and so has an overall length of 59.00m (193ft 7in), compared with 63.70m (209ft 0in) for the standard length aircraft. This allows the A330-200 to seat 256 passengers in a three class configuration, or alternatively 293 in two classes.
Because of its decreased length the A330-200 features enlarged horizontal and vertical tail surfaces (to compensate for the loss of moment arm with the shorter fuselage). Another important change is the addition of a centre fuel tank, which increases the A330-200\'s fuel capacity over the 300\'s, and results in the 200\'s 11,850km (6400nm) range.
Like the A330, engine options are the GE CF6-80, Pratt &amp; Whitney 4000 series and the RollsRoyce Trent 700.
The A330-200 has sold quite strongly since its launch. Among the initial A330-200 customers are, apart from ILFC, Canada 3000, Korean Air, Austrian, Air Transat, Emirates, Swissair, Sabena, Monarch, Asiana, TAM, and Air Lanka.</string>
    <string name="a330t2">The A330-300 is the biggest member of Airbus\' twinjet family and is closely related to the four engined long range A340 with which it shares near identical systems, airframe, flightdeck and wings, the only major difference being the twin (versus four) engine configuration.
The A340 and A330 were launched simultaneously in June 1987. Although developed in parallel the A330-300 made its first flight after the A340, on November 2 1992. It was the first aircraft to achieve simultaneous European Joint Airworthiness Authorities (JAA) and US FAA certification, on October 21 1993. Entry into service took place by the end of that year.
Differences from the A340 aside from the number of engines are slight changes to the wing and internal systems, including fuel tankage. The A330 (like the A340) takes advantage of a number of technologies first pioneered on the A320, including the common advanced EFIS flightdeck with side stick controllers and flybywire computerised flight control system.
While the standard A330-300 shares the same fuselage length as the A340-300, Airbus has studied various stretched (A330-400) and shortened (A330-100 and 200) versions. The shortened A330-200 was formally launched in 1996 as a long range 767-300ER competitor, and is described separately. One stretched, high capacity concept studied for a time featured lower deck seating in place of the forward freight hold.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_a340">A340</string>
    <string name="a340t1">The A340-200 and 300 are the initial variants of the successful quad engined A340 family of long haul widebodies.
The A340 and closely related A330 were launched in June 1987, with the A340\'s first flight occurring on October 25 1991 (an A340-300). The A340 entered service with Lufthansa and Air France in March 1993, following JAA certification the previous December.
The A340 shares the same flightdeck including side stick controllers and EFIS, plus flybywire, basic airframe, systems, fuselage and wing with the A330 (the flightdeck is also common to the A320 series). Power is from four CFM56s, the four engine configuration being more efficient for long range flights (as twins need more power for a given weight for engine out on takeoff performance) and free from ETOPS restrictions.
The A340-300 has the same fuselage length as the A330-300, while the shortened A340-200 trades seating capacity for greater range (first flight April 1 1992).
The heavier A340-300E is available in 271,000kg (597,450lb) and 275,000kg (606,275lb) max takeoff weights, their typical ranges with 295 passengers are 13,155km (7100nm) and 13,525km (7300nm) respectively. Power for these models is from 152.3kN (34,000lb) CFM56-5C4s (the most powerful CFM56s built). The first A340-300Es were delivered to Singapore Airlines in April 1996.
The 275,000kg (606,275lb) max takeoff weight A340-8000 is based on the 200 but has extra fuel in three additional rear cargo hold tanks and offers a 15,000km (8100nm) range with 232 three class passengers (hence the A340-8000 designation). It too is powered by CFM56-5C4s. One has been built for the Sultan of Brunei.
All versions are offered with underfloor passenger sleepers.</string>
    <string name="a340t2">The 15,740km (8500nm) ultra long range A340-500 and stretched 372 seat A340-600 are new variants of the Airbus A340 family, and are currently the world\'s longest range airliners.
Compared with the A340-300, the A340-600 features a 9.07m (35ft 1in) stretch (5.87m/19ft 3in ahead of the wing and 3.20m/10ft 6in behind), allowing it to seat 372 passengers in a typical three class arrangement. This gives Airbus a true early model 747 replacement and near direct competitor to the 747-400, with similar range, but, Airbus claims, better operating economics (per seat).
The A340-500 meanwhile is stretched by only 3.19m (10ft 6in) compared with the A340-300, and so seats 313 in three classes, but it has a massive range of 15,740km (8500nm), which makes it the longest ranging airliner in the world, capable for example of operating Los Angeles-Singapore nonstop.
The two new A340 models share a common wing. The wing is based on the A330/A340\'s but is 1.6m (5.2ft) longer and has a tapered wingbox insert, increasing wing area and fuel capacity. Both models feature three fuselage plugs. The other change to the A340 airframe is the use of the A330-200 twin\'s larger fin and enlarged horizontal area stabilisers. To cope with the increased weights the centre undercarriage main gear is a four wheel bogie, rather than a two wheel unit.
Both new A340s have a high degree of commonality with the A330 and other A340 models. They feature Airbus\' common two crew flightdeck, but with some improvements such as LCD rather than CRT displays and modernised systems.
The A340-500 is powered by four 236kN (53,000lb) thrust Rolls-Royce Trent 556 turbofans, and the A340-600 by the 249kN (56,000lb) thrust Trent 556.
The commercial launch for the A340-500/600 was at the 1997 Paris Airshow, the program\'s industrial launch was in December that year when Virgin Atlantic ordered eight A340-600s and optioned eight. First flight of the A340-600 was made on April 23, 2001. After a 1600 hour flight test program, certification was received on May 29, 2002. Virgin Atlantic took delivery of its first A340-600 at the 2002 Farnborough International Airshow, and began commercial services in August.
The A340-500 made its first flight on February 11, 2002, and was certificated on December 3 after 400 hours of flight test.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_a380">A380</string>
    <string name="a380t1">The 555 seat, double deck Airbus A380 is the world\'s largest airliner, easily eclipsing Boeing\'s 747. The A380 base model is the 555 seat A380-800 (launch customer Emirates). Potential future models include the 590 ton MTOW 10,410km (5620nm) A380-800F freighter, able to carry a 150 tonne payload, and the stretched, 656 seat, A380-900.
Airbus first began studies on a very large 500 seat airliner in the early 1990s. The European manufacturer saw developing a competitor and successor to the Boeing 747 as a strategic play to end Boeing\'s dominance of the very large airliner market and round out Airbus\' product line-up.
Airbus began engineering development work on such an aircraft, then designated the A3XX, in June 1994. Airbus studied numerous design configurations for the A3XX and gave serious consideration to a single deck aircraft which would have seated 12 abreast and twin vertical tails. However Airbus settled upon a twin deck configuration, largely because of the significantly lighter structure required.
Key design aims include the ability to use existing airport infrastructure with little modifications to the airports, and direct operating costs per seat 15-20% less than those for the 747-400. With 49% more floor space and only 35% more seating than the previous largest aircraft, Airbus is ensuring wider seats and aisles for more passenger comfort. Using the most advanced technologies, the A380 is also designed to have 10-15% more range, lower fuel burn and emissions, and produce less noise.
The A380 features an advanced version of the Airbus common two crew cockpit, with pull-out keyboards for the pilots, extensive use of composite materials such as GLARE (an aluminium/glass fibre composite), and four 302 to 374kN (68,000 to 84,000lb) class Rolls-Royce Trent 900 or Engine Alliance (General Electric/Pratt &amp; Whitney) GP7200 turbofans now under development.</string>
    <string name="a380t2">On July 24, 2000, Emirates became the first customer making a firm order commitment, followed by Air France, International Lease Finance Corporation (ILFC), Singapore Airlines, Qantas and Virgin Atlantic. Together these companies completed the 50 orders needed to launch the programme.
On receipt of the required 50th launch order commitment, the Airbus A3XX was renamed A380 and officially launched on December 19, 2000. The out of sequence A380 designation was chosen as the \"8\" represents the cross-section of the twin decks. In early 2001 the general configuration design was frozen, and metal cutting for the first A380 component occurred on January 23, 2002, at Nantes in France. In 2002 more than 6000 people were working on A380 development.
Apart from the prime contractors in France, Germany, the United Kingdom and Spain, components for the A380 airframe are also manufactured by industrial partners in Australia, Austria, Belgium, Canada, Finland, Italy, Japan, South Korea, Malaysia, Netherlands, Sweden, Switzerland and the United States. A380 final assembly is taking place in Toulouse, France, with interior fitment in Hamburg, Germany. Major A380 assemblies are transported to Toulouse by ship, barge and road.
On January 18, 2005, the first Airbus A380 was officially revealed in a lavish ceremony, attended by 5000 invited guests including the French, German, British and Spanish president and prime ministers, representing the countries that invested heavily in the 10-year aircraft program, and the CEOs of the 14 A380 customers, who had placed firm orders for 149 aircraft by then.
Later, the following companies also ordered the A380: FedEx (the launch customer for the A380-800F freighter), Qatar Airways, Lufthansa, Korean Air, Malaysia Airlines, Etihad Airways, Thai Airways and UPS.
However, in 2007, amid production delays, Airbus announced that it was halting design work on the A380 freighter to concentrate on the passenger version of the aircraft. FedEx and UPS canceled their orders for the aircraft.
Five prototypes were used in the flight test programme, which was heavily delayed due to problems with configuration management and wiring issues. The first flight occurred in August 2006, and entry into commercial service, with Singapore Airlines, took place in October 2007.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_a310">A310</string>
    <string name="a310t1">The A310 first began life as the A300B10, one of a number of projected developments and derivatives of Airbus\' original A300B airliner.
While based on the larger A300, the A310 introduced a number of major changes. The fuselage was shortened by 13 frames compared to the A300B, reducing seating to around 200 to 230 passengers and a new higher aspect ratio wing of smaller span and area was developed. New and smaller horizontal tail surfaces, fly-by-wire outboard spoilers and a two crew EFIS flightdeck were incorporated, while the engine pylons were common to suit both engine options.</string>
    <string name="a310t2">The first flight of the A310 occurred on April 3 1982, after the program was launched in July 1978. Service entry was with Lufthansa in April 1983. Early production A310s did not have the small winglets that became a feature of later build A310-200s and the A310-300. The A310-300 is a longer range development of the base A310-200, and has been in production since 1985. This version can carry a further 7000kg (15,430lb) of fuel in the tailplane.
The A310-200F freighter is available new build or as a conversion of existing aircraft (13 A310s were converted to freighters for Federal Express by Airbus partner Daimler Benz [now DaimlerChrysler] Aerospace Airbus). The A310-200C convertible passenger/freighter first entered service with Dutch operator Martinair in 1984.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_a300">A300</string>
    <string name="a300t1">The A300-600 development of the earlier A300B4 incorporated a number of significant improvements and refinements, foremost being a two crew flightdeck and increased range.
Apart from the two crew EFIS cockpit, with digital avionics based on that developed for the A310, changes included the A310\'s tail empennage which increased freight and passenger payloads, small winglets (an option from 1989, standard from 1991), simplified systems, greater use of composites, Fowler flaps and increased camber on the wings, new brakes and APU, and improved payload/range through an extensive drag reducing airframe clean up and new engines. First flight for the A300-600 was on July 8 1983, the first airline delivery was in March 1984.</string>
    <string name="a300t2">The A300-600 was further developed into the longer range A300-600R, its extended range courtesy of a fuel trim tank in the tailplane and higher maximum takeoff weights. First flight was on December 9 1987, first delivery was April 20 1988 (to American Airlines).
Convertible freight/passenger versions of all variants of the A300 have been offered, as has the all freight A300F4-600. The first new build pure freighter A300, one of 36 ordered for Federal Express, flew in December 1993. UPS is another major A300-600F customer, following its September 1998 order for 30. Airbus also offers conversion packages of existing passenger A300s into freighters with a left side forward freight door and strengthened floor.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display737">Boeing 737</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display737_news">737 News</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display747">Boeing 747</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display747_news">Boeing 747 News</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display757">Boeing 757</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display767">Boeing 767</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display767_news">Boeing 767 News</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display777">Boeing 777</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display777_news">Boeing 777 News</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display787_news">Boeing 787 News</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display737_os">737 Original Series</string>
    <string name="b737ost1">The 737-100 and 200 are the first generation production models of the world\'s most successful jet airliner family, Boeing\'s 737 twinjet.\n\n
        The 737 was conceived as a short range small capacity airliner to round out the Boeing jet airliner family beneath the 727 and 707. Announced in February 1965, the 737 was originally envisioned as a 60 to 85 seater, although following consultation with launch customer Lufthansa, a 100 seat design was settled upon.\n\n
        Boeing was far behind its competitors when the 737 was launched, as rival aircraft BAC 1-11, Douglas DC-9, and Fokker F28 were already into flight certification. To expedite development, Boeing used 60% of the structure and systems of the existing 727, the most notable being the fuselage cross-section. This fuselage permitted six-abreast seating compared to the rival 1-11 and DC-9\'s five-abreast layout.\n\n
        The 737-100 made its first flight on April 9 1967 and entered service in February 1968 with Lufthansa, while the last of 30 built was delivered to Malaysia-Singapore Airlines in October 1969.</string>
    <string name="b737ost2">On April 5, 1965 Boeing announced an order by United Airlines for 40 737s. United wanted a slightly larger airplane than the 737-100. So Boeing stretched the fuselage 91 centimeters (36 in) ahead of, and 102 cm (40 in) behind the wing. The longer version was designated 737-200, with the original short-body aircraft becoming the 737-100.\n\n
        Developments of the -200 include the -200C convertible and quick change -200QC, while an unprepared airfield kit was also offered. The definitive 737-200 Advanced appeared in 1971, featuring minor aerodynamic refinements, more powerful engines and a greater fuel capacity giving it a 15% increase in payload and range over the original -200s.</string>
    <string name="b737ost3">Sales of the 737-200 far exceeded that of the shorter -100 and the 737-200 remained in production until 1988, by which time it had been superseded by the improved 737-300, after 1114 had been built. Many have been fitted with Stage 3 engine hushkits, and a number of passenger aircraft have been converted with cargo doors.\n\n
        The USAF ordered 19 as navigation trainers, and some were later converted to standard transport aircraft as CT-43A. A few other air forces received 737-200s to serve in general transport, surveillance or VIP transport tasks.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display737_cs">Display737CS</string>

</resources>